Kapil Lalchandani

Network Consulting Engineer at Cisco

Summary

More than 12 years of experience in Planning, Designing, and Implementation of Cisco products based Network Solutions for customers.

Extensive knowledge in Business Video Solutions. Experience of working on Voice and Data Networks CCNA, CCNP Certified

Have worked in various verticals including ISPs, Financial, Enterprises and System Integrators.

Specialties: Designing and Implementing Business Video Solutions (TelePresence Exchange, Capture-Transform-Share, Jabber Video, Virtual Classroom Solutions, ECDS, Videoscape, CUCM, VCS-C/E, TMS, CTMS, TelePresence Server, TelePresence Conductor, MXE 3500/5600, Digital Signage)
Routing & Switching and Security

Experience

Network Consulting Engineer - Business Video at Cisco Systems India

July 2007 - Present (9 years 9 months)

SME for Business Video Solutions sales, design and implementation.

Senior Network Engineer at Symantec

January 2006 - June 2007 (1 year 6 months)

Level II, Network Engineer.

Manage Escalations, Change Management for IT Network Infrastructure.

Sr. Network Engineer at Network Solutions

September 2004 - October 2005 (1 year 2 months)

Working in the Global Management Center as a Level II Engineer, Designing and Implementing Customer Network Upgrades.

Senior Network Engineer at Exatt Technologies Pvt. Ltd

September 2003 - August 2004 (1 year)

Senior Network Engineer

Languages

Hindi

Sindhi

Punjabi

Gujrati

Skills & Expertise

Cisco Technologies

SIP Trunking

Unified Communications

Telepresence

Digital Media Services

Cisco Telepresence

Video Conferencing

ECDS

TelePresence Exchange

CTX

Tandberg

Cisco Routing & Switching

Pre-sales

Solution Architecture

Firewalls

Streaming Media

Data Center

Networking

Cisco Call Manager

QoS

Security

Network Architecture

CCNP

Cisco Routers

Cisco IOS

MPLS

Network Design

Routing

CCNA

BGP

OSPF

ΙP

Switches

Quality of Service (QoS)

Education

CHM College

Bachelors, Commerce, 1996 - 2001

Fatima High School

S.S.C, 1984 - 1995

Interests

Gadgets

New Technology

Driving

Traveling

Kapil Lalchandani

Network Consulting Engineer at Cisco



3 people have recommended Kapil

"Kapil is hard working in nature and calm. He is an expert in Networking field especially in UC Video collaboration technologies (like Cisco Telepresence). His attitude of constant learning both professionally and personally is a nice quality of him. He is and will be very good asset to any organization."

— Ashok Kumar Boinpally, managed Kapil indirectly at Cisco Systems India

"Kapil is hardworking, dedicated, organized and very professional. It has been a pleasure to work with him. His warm personality and professionalism creates a foundation of trust which enables and establishes relationships with clients and his peers at Cisco. He is full of creativity and knows how to articulate his vision."

— Ali Mehdi, worked with Kapil at Cisco Systems India

"Kapil is a very hard and dedicated professional. He is self motivated and enjoys challenges. I have personally seen him grow interms of responsibilities and I wish him all the best."

— Sanjeev Mehra, managed Kapil at Exatt Technologies Pvt. Ltd

Contact Kapil on LinkedIn